Guide to the Chinese Gaming Counters Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Gaming Counters with Unidentified Provenance, circa 1700-circa 1840; Series II; (124 items)
  - Monogram and Crest
    - Monogram "FHM" and a Crest of a Lion's Head
      - Shuttle counter with a drilled border and a crest of a lion's head and neck erased on a torse above the monogram "FHM" and flanked by flowers on both sides., circa 1790-1810 (Box 1, Folder 218)
    - Monogram "FM" and a Crest of a Female Goat
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a geometric border and a crest of a female goat tilting a spear between its forehooves on a torse above a monogram "FM." Both sides flanked by flowers., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 219)
        Verso of a Chinese man sitting and sleeping at a table.
    - Monogram "G" and a Crest of an Arm Embowed Holding a Banner
      - Shuttle counter with a geometric border and a crest of an arm embowed, vested, cuffed, and holding in the hand a banner of six stripes and a canton with a cross on a torse above a monogram "G" and flanked by flowers., circa 1780-1790 (Box 1, Folder 220)
    - Monogram "G" and a Crest of a Stag's Head
      - Shuttle counter with a drilled border and a crest of a stags's head and neck couped on a torse., circa 1790-1810 (Box 1, Folder 221)
        Verso has monogram "G."
    - Monogram "H" and a Crest of a Dexter Arm
      - Oval counter with a drilled border and a crest of a dexter arm in armor embowed and holding a banner., circa 1790-1810 (Box 1, Folder 222)
        Verso has monogram "H."
      - Round counter with a drilled border and a crest of a dexter arm in armor embowed and holding a banner., circa 1790-1810 (Box 1, Folder 223)
    - Monogram "I" and a Crest of a Dove
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a reserves border and a crest of a dove trussed above a ducal hat and the monogram "I.", circa 1760-1790 (Box 1, Folder 224)
    - Monogram "ILS" and a Crest of a Griffin's Head
      - Rectangle counter with a geometric border and a crest of a griffin's head erased on a torse., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 225)
        Verso has monogram "ILS."
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a geometric border and a crest of a griffin's erased couped on a torse., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 226)
      - Round counter with a geometric border and a crest of a griffin's head erased on a torse., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 227)
    - Monogram "IWSB" and a Crest of a Demi-Lion
      - Shuttle counter with a drilled border and a crest of a demi-lion rampant on a torse and flanked by flowers., circa 1780-1800 (Box 1, Folder 228)
        Verso has monogram "IWSB" and diapering.
      - Round counter with a drilled border and a crest of a demi-lion rampant on a torse., circa 1780-1800 (Box 1, Folder 229)
        "Verso has monogram "TWSB" and diapering.
    - Monogram "JCS" and a Crest of a Tree
      - Shuttle counter with a geometric border and a crest of a tree issuing from a tower on a torse., circa 1800-1810 (Box 1, Folder 230)
        "Verso has monogram "JCS."
      - Round counter with a geometric border and a crest of a tree issuing from a tower on a torse., circa 1800-1810 (Box 1, Folder 231)
        "Verso has monogram "JCS" and diapering.
    - Monogram "JH" and a Crest of a Demi-Eagle
      - Oblong rectangle counter with deep carving an a floral border and a crest of a demi-eagle with an oak sprig in its beak above monogram "JH" and flanked by a scene with a bird and dog., circa 1820-1840 (Box 1, Folder 232)
      - Oblong rectangle counter with deep carving an a floral border and a crest of a demi-eagle with an oak sprig in its beak above monogram "JH" and flanked by a scene with a moth and a bird., circa 1820-1840 (Box 1, Folder 233)
    - Monogram "JWS" and a Crest of a Demi-Bird
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a key fret border and a crest of a demi-bird rising on a torse above the monogram "JWS" and flanked by two scenes of birds, circa 1790-1840 (Box 1, Folder 234)
    - Monogram "P" and a Crest of a Tree
      - Oval counter with a drilled border and a crest of a tree growing out of a palisade on a torse and above monogram "P" and flanked by flowers., circa 1780-1800 (Box 1, Folder 235)
    - Monogram "R" and a Crest of a Dexter Arm
      - Shuttle counter with a Queen Charlotte border and a crest of an armored dexter arm embowed and holding in its hand a dagger on a torse above the monogram "R.", circa 1780-1790 (Box 1, Folder 236)
    - Monogram "RSS" and a Crest of a Unicorn's Head
      - Shuttle counter with a drilled border and a crest of a unicorn's head and neck on a torse above the monogram "RSS.", circa 1790-1810 (Box 1, Folder 237)
    - Monogram "SAH" and a Crest of a Dragon's Head
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a drilled border and a crest of a dragon's head and neck erased on a torse above the monogram "SAH" and flanked by flowers., circa 1780-1800 (Box 1, Folder 238)
    - Monogram "THB" and a Crest of an Eagle's Head
      - Shuttle counter with a drilled border and a crest of an eagle's head erased on a torse and flanked by flowers., circa 1780-1800 (Box 1, Folder 239)
        Verso has monogram "THB" and diapering.
    - Monogram "TIR" and a Crest of a Crescent
      - Shuttle counter with a drilled border and a crest of a crescent on a torse above a monogram "TIR" and flanked by flowers., circa 1780-1800 (Box 1, Folder 240)
    - Monogram "TPI" and a Crest of a Demi-Lion
      - Shuttle counter with a drilled border and an escutcheon with a monogram "TPI" above a crest of a demi-lion rampant on a torse, with the escutcheon below a helm and flanked by flowers., circa 1780-1800 (Box 1, Folder 241)
    - Monogram "TTS" and a Crest of a Lion
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a geometric border and crest of a lion rampant on a torse above a monogram "TTS.", circa 1800-1810 (Box 1, Folder 242)
    - Monogram "WC" and a Crest of a Lion's Head
      - Round counter with a swags border and a crest of a lion's head and neck couped and on a torse above the monogram "WC.", circa 1770-1840 (Box 1, Folder 243)
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a swags border and a crest of a lion's head and neck couped and on a torse above the monogram "WC.", circa 1770-1840 (Box 1, Folder 244)
    - Monogram "WDIG" and a Crest of a Phoenix's Head
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a Queen Charlotte border and a crest of a phoenix's head wearing a crown and neck erased on a torse above the monogram "WDIG.", circa 1780-1790 (Box 1, Folder 245)
    - Monogram "WH" and a Crest of a Dove
      - Shuttle counter with a drilled border and a crest of a dove proper with a sprig in its beak on a torse above the monogram "WH.", circa 1780-1790 (Box 1, Folder 246)
    - Monogram "WH" and a Crest of a Unicorn's Head
      - Rectangle counter with a drilled border and a crest of a unicorn's head and neck couped on a torse above the monogram "WH" and flanked by flowers., circa 1780-1790 (Box 1, Folder 247)
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a drilled border and a crest of a unicorn's head and neck couped on a torse above the monogram "WH" and flanked by flowers., circa 1780-1790 (Box 1, Folder 248)
      - Round counter with a drilled border and a crest of a dove proper with a sprig in its beak on a torse above the monogram "WH." Both sides flanked by flowers.", circa 1780-1790 (Box 1, Folder 249)
    - Monogram "WHA" and a Crest of an Eagle
      - Oval counter with a line border and a crest of an eagle rising and wings addorsed above a torse and the monogram "WHA.", circa 1780-1810 (Box 1, Folder 250)
    - Monogram "WR" and a Crest of a Stag's Head
      - Round counter with a swags border and a crest of a stag's head above an escutcheon with a monogram "WR.", circa 1770-1840 (Box 1, Folder 251)
        Very worn counter.
    - Monogram "WSCC" and a Crest of a Chained Bear
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a Queen Charlotte border and a crest of a chained bear holding an ax on a torse above the monogram "WSCC.", circa 1780-1790 (Box 1, Folder 252)
  - Crest Only
    Arranged alphabetically by crest, with demi-animal crests after proper animal crests.
    - Crest of an Arm
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a fretted border and a crest of a embowed dexter arm wearing armor and holding a battle axe on a torse and flanked by a scene with two birds., circa 1820-1840 (Box 1, Folder 253)
      - Rectangle counter with a fretted border and a crest of a embowed dexter arm wearing armor and holding a battle axe on a torse and flanked by a scene with two birds., circa 1820-1840 (Box 1, Folder 254)
    - Crest of a Beaver
      - Round counter with a drilled border and a crest of a beaver proper on a torse., circa 1780-1800 (Box 1, Folder 255)
    - Crest of a Bird
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a fretted border and a crest of a bird rising on a torse and flanked by a scene with two birds., circa 1820-1840 (Box 1, Folder 256)
        Verso of three Chinese men, one man seated and holding a fan, and a village scene.
      - Rectangle counter with a fretted border and a crest of a bird rising on a torse and flanked by a scene with two birds., circa 1820-1840 (Box 1, Folder 257)
      - Round counter with a fretted border and a crest of a bird rising on a torse and flanked by a scene with two birds., circa 1820-1840 (Box 1, Folder 258)
    - Crest of a Demi-Bird
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a fretted border and a crest of a demi-bird rising on a torse and flanked by a scene with a moth and a bird., circa 1820-1840 (Box 1, Folder 259)
    - Crest of a Bull's Head
      - Fish-shaped counter with a crest of a bull's head coped issuant from a mural crown on a torse., circa 1720-1760 (Box 1, Folder 260)
    - Crest of a Club
      - Oblong rectangle counter with deep carving an a floral border and a crest of a dexter cubit arm holding a club on a torse and flanked by a scene with a bird and a dog., circa 1820-1840 (Box 1, Folder 261)
        Verso of two Chinese men, a Chinese woman, and a village scene.
    - Crest of a Dragon
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a drilled border and a crest of a dragon rampant on a torse. Both sides flanked by flowers., circa 1790-1830 (Box 1, Folder 262)
        Verso of a Chinese man weaving a basket.
    - Crest of a Demi-Dragon Holding a Battle-Axe
      - Round counter with a drilled border and a crest of a demi-dragon rampant and holding a battle-axe on a torse., circa 1790-1830 (Box 1, Folder 263)
        Verso of a Chinese man on a mountain.
    - Crest of a Demi-Dragon Holding a Lizard
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a geometric border and a crest of a demi-dragon rampant and wings addorsed and holding a lizard., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 264)
        Verso has a Chinese woman holding a fan and buildings.
    - Crest of a Dragon's Head
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a geometric floral border and a crest of a dragon's head and neck erased., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 265)
        Verso has a Chinese man and a building.
      - Rectangle counter with a geometric floral border and a crest of a dragon's head and neck erased., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 266)
        Verso has a Chinese figure sitting at a table with a leaf on it.
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a geometric floral border and a crest of a dragon's head and neck erased., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 267)
        Verso has a Chinese man carrying a bundle and a building.
    - Crest of an Eagle
      - Oblong rectangle counter with deep carving an a floral border and a crest of an eagle displayed and wearing a crown out of a marquess crown and flanked by a scene with two dogs., circa 1820-1840 (Box 1, Folder 268)
    - Crest of a Demi-Eagle
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a vine and moth border and a crest of a demi-eagle displayed on a torse and flanked by a scene with a bird and dog., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 269)
      - Round counter with a vine and moth border and a crest of a demi-eagle displayed on a torse and flanked by a scene with a bird and dog., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 270)
        Verso of two Chinese men holding tools and a village scene.
    - Crest of a Double-Headed Demi-Eagle
      - Round counter with a vine and moth border and a crest of a double-headed demi-eagle wings displayed and elevated on a torse and flanked by a scene with two birds., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 271)
        Verso of three Chinese men, one man writing, and a village scene.
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a vine and moth border and a crest of a double-headed demi-eagle wings displayed and elevated on a torse and flanked by a scene with two birds., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 272)
        Verso of a Chinese woman and two Chinese men and a village scene.
      - Rectangle counter with a vine and moth border and a crest of a double-headed demi-eagle wings displayed and elevated on a torse and flanked by a scene with a cricket and bird., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 273)
        "Verso of two Chinese women, one woman holding an umbrella, a Chinese man, and a village scene.
    - Crest of an Eagle Rising
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a vine and moth border and a crest of an eagle rising and holding a snake in its dexter foot., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 274)
        Verso of three Chinese men and buildings.
      - Round counter with a vine and moth border and a crest of an eagle rising and holding a snake in its dexter foot., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 275)
      - Rectangle counter with a vine and moth border and a crest of an eagle rising and holding a snake in its dexter foot and flanked by a scene with a bird and beatle., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 276)
    - Crest of an Escallop
      - Round counter with a vine and moth border and a crest of an escallop between two wings on a torse surrounded by a village scene., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 277)
    - Crest of a Falcon
      - Oblong rectangle counter with deep carving an a floral border and a crest of a falcon with wings trussed on a torse flanked by a scene with a Chinese man and dog., circa 1820-1840 (Box 1, Folder 278)
        Verso of two Chinese men, a bird, and a village scene.
    - Crest of a Goat
      - Round counter with a drilled border and a crest of a goat's head and neck couped on a torse and flanked by flowers., circa 1780-1800 (Box 1, Folder 279)
      - Shuttle counter with a drilled border and a crest of a goat's head and neck couped on a torse and flanked by flowers., circa 1780-1800 (Box 1, Folder 280)
    - Crest of a Hand
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a key fret border and a crest of a dexter hand holding hops on a torse., circa 1790-1840 (Box 1, Folder 281)
        Verso of a Chinese man holding a banner.
    - Crest of a Hare
      - Round counter with a line border and a crest of a hare lodged and regardant on both sides., circa 1700-1770 (Box 1, Folder 282)
    - Crest of a Hawk
      - Rectangle counter with a line border and a crest of a hawk with wings trussed on a torse., circa 1750-1780 (Box 1, Folder 283)
        Verso has a scene of two lovebirds on a torse beside a tower.
    - Crest of a Hind
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a crest of a hind's head with an oak sprig in its mouth and in a ducal crown on only one side., circa 1770-1730 (Box 1, Folder 284)
    - Crest of a Horse
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a vine and moth border and a crest of a horse's head and neck couped on a torse and flanked by a scene with two moths., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 285)
    - Crest of a Demi-Lion
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a fretted border and a crest of a demi-lion rampant in a marquess crown flanked by a scene with two birds., circa 1820-1840 (Box 1, Folder 286)
        Verso of a Chinese woman and two Chinese men, one man carrying a hoe, and a village scene.
    - Crest of a Demi-Lion and Holding a Battle-Axe
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a drilled border a crest of a demi-lion rampant holding a battle-axe in its paws on a torse., circa 1790-1810 (Box 1, Folder 287)
        Verso of a Chinese man holding a fan.
    - Crest of a Demi-Lion and Holding a Sword
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a line border and a crest of a demi-lion rampant and holding a sword in its dexter paw above a torse., circa 1750-1770 (Box 1, Folder 288)
    - Crest of a Martlet
      - Fish-shaped counter with scales and a crest of a martlet on a torse on both sides., circa 1720-1760 (Box 1, Folder 289)
    - Crest of a Martlet Above a Helm
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a line border and a crest of a martlet on a torse above a helm., circa 1760-1770 (Box 1, Folder 290)
    - Crest of a Palm Branch
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a vine and moth border and a crest of a windswept palm branch on a torse., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 291)
        Verso of a Chinese man carrying a load.
    - Crest of a Spur
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a vine and moth border and a crest of a winged spur on a torse and flanked by a scene with two birds., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 292)
    - Crest of a Squirrel
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a line border and a crest of a squirrel cracking a nut proper and supported by mulberries., circa 1760-1770 (Box 1, Folder 293)
    - Crest of a Stag's Head
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a geometric border and a crest of a stags's head and neck couped on a torse., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 294)
        Verso of a Chinese man running and holding a box.
      - Round counter with a geometric border and a crest of a stags's head and neck couped on a torse., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 295)
        Verso of a Chinese man running and holding a flower.
    - Crest of a Stag's Head Affrontée
      - Rectangle counter with a vine and moth border and a crest of a stag's head affrontée., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 296)
        Verso of a Chinese man and buildings.
      - Round counter with a vine and moth border and a crest of a stag's head affrontée., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 297)
        Verso of a Chinese man holding a fan and buildings.
    - Crest of a Talbot
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a drilled border and a crest of a talbot sejant on a torse., circa 1790-1810 (Box 1, Folder 298)
        Verso of a Chinese woman and flowers.
    - Crest of a Thistle
      - Round counter with a crest of a thistle leaved proper on a torse and surrounded by a scene with a spider and moth., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 299)
        Verso of two Chinese men, one man carrying a yoke, and a village scene.
    - Crest of a Three Ovals
      - Round counter with a line border and a crest of three ovals., circa 1730-1770 (Box 1, Folder 300)
        Counter is damaged.
    - Crest of a Willow Tree
      - Round counter with a geometric border and a crest of a willow tree flanked by flowers., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 301)
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a geometric border and a crest of a willow tree flanked by flowers., circa 1800-1830 (Box 1, Folder 302)
  - Monogram Only
    - Monogram "H"
      - Oblong rectangle counter with a line border and a monogram "H" below an earl crown., circa 1760-1770 (Box 1, Folder 303)
      - Round counter with a line border and a monogram "H" below an earl crown., circa 1760-1770 (Box 1, Folder 304)